Friends, recently the Central Government
brought the next generation GST reforms.
Within this reform, GST on health insurance and
life insurance was completely reduced to
zero.  The government thought long ago
that this GST,
especially 18% GST in health insurance, is
too high.  Because health
insurance, which is a day to day
life product i.e. an essential
product in today's date, the government thought that it is
needed by the people like daily needs.  Like
food, clothing and shelter.  Ok?  So here,
along with food, clothing and shelter,
you should also add insurance as it is necessary for you in today's date.
Because if a medical
emergency occurs, then the person who is at this level cannot
fall straight down.  That means
he can directly become poor from rich.  Just
a medical emergency.  So basically,
if we look at this GST, you
cannot believe that after 22nd this
GST is going to be totally null.  Yes
friends, this is a very big
good news for you because you can purchase a health
insurance or term insurance which is
cheap.  But
friends, if we talk about health insurance,
in reality people do not know
about actual health insurance.  There are
many health insurance
products available in the market today.  But there are a
lot of cappings, a lot of
restrictions and cooperation in those health insurances.  That means
if they go to get admitted in the hospital,
they face a lot of trouble there
because if the claim comes,
say ₹ lakh, then it is possible that ₹ 1 lakh has to be
paid from the pocket.  So there are many
restrictions in health insurance.
So friends,
if you want to purchase a health insurance in my presence, then
I will make it very easy for you in this video
because zero GST means which
plan you have to purchase, which
riders you have to add in which plan, which
riders you do
not need to add, right how much coverage you should take
and which coverage will be best for you,
in which city you are living,
how much coverage you should have according to that, so I am going to
talk about it in full detail in this video, so friends, after
nil GST, I will discuss these three plans
which are the best plans in the market.
But if you have to
choose one plan out of the three, which one will you choose
?  So at the end of the video I will
tell you some tips.  With the help of those tips,
you can select the best plan from among the three.
Friends,
before starting the video, just a quick reminder, if
you have not subscribed to the channel then do it
and press the bell icon
so that you can get such important videos
through this channel.  So friends,
if we talk about comparison, I selected three plans
from the market.  The first plan
is the Optimus Secure plan of HDFC Airbo company.  At
second place is ICICI LBRD
's 11 plan and the plan at third place is
NIBA's Resource 3.0 plan.  So let
us know about the USB of all three plans and
what unique selling points
are available in those plans.  So
friends, first of all if we talk about HDFC Ago
Optimus Secure.  Let us
talk about the USP of this plan here.  The first
USP is Secure Benefit.  That means,
whatever sum you choose, for example,
if you
take a sum of Rs 50 lakh, then your sum of Rs 50 lakh assured with
secure benefit becomes Rs 1 crore from day one.
Next if we talk about
Plus Benefit, what happens through Plus Benefit is
that your Samacord will increase by 50% every
year.  That means you took Samard worth Rs 50 lakh.
Next year your Samard will be worth Rs 75
lakh.  Then in the next year
you will have a sum of Rs 1 crore.  Another
benefit is pre-existing diseases
i.e. A B C D asthma, BP,
cholesterol and diabetes.  You can get cover from 31 days
with extra premium
or you can get cover by taking writer.
Next friends, if we
talk about the next plan, it is ICICI LB
's 11 plan.  What are the USPs of Element Plan, let
us talk about it. First of all,
if we talk about your benefit, it is
power booster. Right, through power booster,
basically your sum will
increase by 100% every year and
this will continue for life as long as you keep the policy
in force, your sum will keep increasing.
Suppose you took a policy of Rs 50 lakh,
then of Rs 1 crore, then of Rs 1.5 crore, then
every year your sum will keep
increasing by 100%, that is, whatever your
sum, the same sum will keep increasing for you
every year.  Right?  Next thing we talk about
is jump start.  If
you take Jump Start rider, then
basically your hypertension, diabetes,
obesity, asthma and hyperlipidemia will be
covered here for 31 days with
extra premium.  The next rider
is Infinity Care.  If you
take Infinity Care Rider, then
you can make Infinity Care claim once in the entire policy term.
What is the USP of Re 3.0
?  Let us see.  The first USP that the
company introduced for the first time
in the health insurance industry is the
option of unlimited sum insured.  Meaning there
is no concept of sum insured here.  You will get unlimited sum
insured.  Even if your first claim is of Rs 1 crore
, Rs 10 crore, Rs 20 crore or Rs
50 crore, the company is
ready to pay your claim whenever it comes.
Right?  So here the option of unlimited calls
is available in RESO 3.0.  Next,
if we talk about it, there are 145 pre-existing
diseases which you can cover from day one.
If we talk about this, there is
another benefit in this plan and that is Lock the Clock.
Lock the clock means that the
premium changes according to your age band, for example, if
you are 35 years old.  Now
what will happen in 36?  Your premium will increase.  But
here your premium will not increase due to age band.  There is an
option here which
is an inbuilt option or you do not need to take a rider.
That is Lock the Clock.  With Lock the
Clock, your premium will never increase according to your age band.
But if you take the claim
then the premium will increase.
Another reason is that
if the company increases the premium due to inflation, then your
premium will increase.  But this
is the only benefit.  If your premium increases according to the age band, then the
premium will not
increase here.  Because of Lock the Clock.  Friends,
if you have to choose any plan, if you have to
purchase a health insurance policy
, then
you should look at the claim settlement ratio of health insurance companies.  So
if we talk about claim settlement ratio, the
claim settlement ratio of HDFC Air is
99%.  The claim settlement ratio of ICIC LBA
is 97% and that of Nibu is
92%.
If we talk about the denial claim ratio, that is,
how much premium the company collected and how much
claim they gave against it, then
if we talk about the
in-card claim ratio of HDFC Airgo, it is
81%, if we talk about the in-card claim ratio of ICICI LBRD, it is
79% and if we
talk about the denial claim ratio of NVIV,
it is 59%,
so here if we talk about the claim settlement ratio and
in-card claim ratio, HDFC
Airgo is looking the best.  Right?
Now let's talk about the solvency ratio.  So the
meaning of solvency ratio is
how much liability the company has.
How many assets do they have against them?
Right?  So if we talk about the solvency ratio,
that of HDFC Aero is 1.68.
If we talk about the solvency ratio of ICICI LBD, it
is 2.68.  If we talk about Neebupa, it
is 2.55, that is, against the
liabilities, they have that much
assets.  Right friends,
now let's talk about network hospitals.  When
you purchase any medical from the company,
you should see that there should be
maximum number of cashless hospitals in the network around you.
You must have
heard the news like Care Health Insurance and
Bajaj, their tie up with hospitals is going to be
cancelled.  Cashless will not be
available completely.  But as per the recent news, it is going to be
settled and it has already been settled.
So here
if we talk about network hospitals, friends,
if we talk about network hospitals of HDFC Ergo,
14,000 plus network hospitals
are available with them.  If we talk about ICICI LB,
they have 15,000 plus hospitals.
Complete all
India level basis for cashless.  If we talk about
Nibapa, they have 11,000 plus hospital
cashless services.  After that
friends, if we talk about
any reimbursement process like pre and post, it
goes into reimbursement.  Plus, if any
cashless transaction is denied, you can
claim reimbursement.  So the
reimbursement claim process is basically the same as what used to happen
in many companies today, earlier
you had to make physical deposits.
But what happens today is that the
submission is done online
in the companies' app.  So, in the plans of all three companies,
you can submit your reimbursement to all three companies on online basis.  The
companies provide your claim within a week or 10 days.
Right?  Next friends, if we talk
about Sama S, right, then
how much Sama SARD can you take?
If we talk about HDFC Ergo, in Optimum Secure
you can take Sama S worth Rs 5 lakh, 10 lakh, 15
lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 50 lakh and up to Rs 1 crore in
HDFC Ergo
Optimus Secure plan. Next
friends, if we talk about ICIC lambdar 11
plan, you can take Sama S worth Rs 5 lakh, 7 lakh, 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh,
50 lakh, 1 crore, 3 crore and
according to you.  Next
friends, if we talk about Nibu,
in ReSored 3.0 you get unlimited
sum asor here.  Friends, now let's talk about the policy
tenure, for how many years can you purchase the policy
?  So here if we talk about HDFC Ag Optimum
Security, you can purchase a policy for 1 year, 2 years or 3 years.
Here, if
we talk about the Eleven plan of ICICI LBT,
you can purchase the plan for 1 year, 2 years, 3 years, 4 years and 5 years.
Next, here
you can talk about REST 3.0 on NIBM, you can purchase policy for 1 year, 2
years, 3 years, 4 years and 5 years also.
Friends, now let's talk about
pre and post hospitalization, that is, the
expenses incurred before admission in the hospital and
after discharge basically
go into reimbursement.  So here you get pre and post
hospitalization for 60
and 180 days in HDFC,
in Optimum Secure, you get 90 and 180 days in ICICI LB plan.
If we talk about
VSO 3.0, you get 60 and 180 days pre
and post hospitalization.
Next, if we talk about day care
treatment, day care means that
you do not need to stay in the hospital for 24 hours.  For example,
if any
technology is good today then stone
operations etc. are done.  So basically
you do not need to be admitted for 24 hours.
If you are admitted for 10 hours or even 12 hours
basically, then that admission is called day
care.  So all three plans have old day care
cover.  All daycare will be covered and up to
the entire daycare is covered in all three plans.
Next, if we talk about
modern treatment, friends.  Modern treatment
plays a huge role in your policy.
Right?  Like today, many
surgeries are robotic surgeries.  And
in the coming times, doctors are also preferring
robotic surgery for modern
treatment.  So here in all the three plans, there is
no capping of modern treatment in any way.  So this
is a very big plus point.
If anyone takes any of the three plans, there is
no capping on modern treatment.  Next friends,
if we talk about ambulance, then
up to the
standard ambulance is covered in Optimus Secure.  Talking about road ambulance,
up to 50 road
ambulances are covered in IC Lab's Elevate plan.  So up
to the same road ambulance is covered in all three plans.  Next
friends, if we talk about air ambulance, then
in air ambulance, in Optimus Secure,
you get air ambulance for hospitalization above Rs 5 lakh.
Next, if we talk about IC Lamb
's Elevate plan, here up to the sum of
air ambulance is covered.  If we
talk about Restore 3.0, here
your capping for air ambulance is ₹5 lakh.  Right?
Next friends, if we talk about annual
health checkup.  Annual Health Checkup: Basically,
if we talk about Optimus Secure, you
get annual health checkup.  You get one lakh for Rs 500.  The
maximum annual
health checkup you get is Rs 15,000.
Next, if we talk about the
Eleven plan of Rupees Lombard, here also
you get a health checkup of up to ₹5,000.  You get it
according to the health checkup that is listed for you.
Next, if we talk about ROS 3.0, you
can avail the option of health checkup through a rider.  Next friends, if
we talk about alternative treatment which is
called Ayush treatment like Ayurvedic,
Unani, Homeopathy and Siddha treatment.
So here at Optim Secure, Talk
Up to the Sames is covered.  Alternative treatments are covered in up to 11 plans
in all three plans.
Next, let's talk about
maternity cover.
If you take Optimus Secure plan in maternity cover, then
you
can cover maternity through parenthood rider.  Next, if
we talk about ICICI Lambdar's Elevate Plan,
in which 10% of basic sum
is available after 2 years.  There is some capping here also.
Next, if we talk about Reed 3.0,
you do not get maternity cover.  So
friends, this was the comparison of all three plans
after GST. Basically,
GST will not be applicable on all three plans,
so due to the absence of GST, your
premium has become much cheaper.  So now
in the coming slide we will see
how much premium you have to pay in which plan.
If we have taken the calculation of one age.  Ok
?  Based on that calculation, we
will tell you how much premium you have to pay.
So friends, if we talk about the calculation of premium,
we have taken the premium calculation of a 40 years old male right along with
his wife and two children, that is,
we have calculated the premium of daily answer
accordingly, so if we talk about
how much premium will be there for HDFC R Optima Secure, the
premium is coming for 50
lakhs, that is, 50 lakhs sum assured, we
considered what happens in Optima Secure from day one,
what will be your sum assured with secure benefit, that sum assured gets doubled for you, that
is, it becomes 1 crore sum assured
from day one, so
if we talk about basic coverage of 50 lakhs, the premium will be
₹4588,
that is, ₹458 will be the
premium of HDFC Airgo Optimus
Secure against 50 lakhs,
next if we talk about
Elevate plan of ICIC LB, which is a 40 years old male,
talk about 2 + 2 and 50 lakhs sum assured, the
premium is coming to 44000,
next if we talk about NIV
Right same we have taken calculation of REES 3.0, 40 years
and 2 plus means he has wife and two children,
2 plus 2. If we talk about premium, if we
talk about premium of daily NCR,
we have covered Safeguard Plus.  Plus
we have also added health checkup to it.
In this, a rider has to be added,
even after adding the rider, there is an
option of unlimited sum assured. The premium of the black variant that we have taken is Rs.
42486,
that is, for Rs. 42486 you get unlimited
coverage, along with that consumables are also covered
and health checkup is also covered, right
friends, if you have any plan related
inquiry or you want to purchase a plan
but you are not able to take a decision,
our IRD authorized insurance
advisor will help you, by comparing the best plan
according to you, according to your city, according to
your age, they can
design the best plan for you.
So if you want
you can WhatsApp us.  If you want to
work with an agency,
you want to make a career in health insurance,
you are already an agent but are
not able to work for health insurance, then
also you can contact us.  We
also recruit health insurance agents
across pan India.  Okay guys, that's it for
this video.
You must take advantage of GST.
If you have not taken health insurance then you must take it.
Thank you so much.  See you in the next video.  Till then
bye-by Jai Hind Vande
Mataram.